shop3m.com 2015-12-29

# Privacy Policy | 3M United States

  * Information You Voluntarily Provide:

3M collects the information you knowingly and voluntarily provide in order to benefit from a feature or participate in an activity on a 3M Internet Site. For example, 3M may collect your information so you may receive email alerts, when you complete a survey, or when you ask for product information, ask a question or email us with feedback. In many cases this information may include collection of personal information.

3M only uses your information for the purposes for which you provide it. For example, if you provide your e-mail address when you sign up to receive e-mail alerts, we use your e-mail address to deliver the e-mail alerts you request.

Many of the 3M Internet Sites permit you to make choices about the use of your personal information. In most cases, we ask you to indicate your choices at the time and on the page where you provide your personal information.

We may also use the information we collect on 3M Internet Sites for various business purposes such as customer service, fraud prevention, improving our products and services, or providing you and your company with information and offers we believe may be of interest to you. We may also remove all the personally identifiable information and use the rest for historical, statistical or scientific purposes.

  * Information Automatically Gathered:

3M collects information sent to us automatically by your web browser. This information typically includes the IP address of your Internet service provider, the name of your operating system (such as Macintosh® or Windows®) and the name and version of your browser (such as Internet Explorer® or Safari®). The information we receive depends on the settings on your web browser. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings.

We use this information to help us improve our sites and make them more compatible with the technology used by our Internet visitors.

  * Cookies and Similar Technologies:

A “cookie” is a file of information placed on your device when you visit a website. Cookies and similar technologies can enhance your user experience by saving your preferences, personalizing your online experience, holding items in your shopping cart, and sometimes providing you with advertising which is tailored to your interests.

All of our 3M Internet Sites use “session cookies”. A session cookie does not identify you personally and expires after you close your browser. For example, when you use the 3M Product Catalog, we place a session cookie to note what pages you have viewed. We can use this information to provide you recommendations of other products that may be of interest.

Some 3M Internet sites also use “persistent cookies”. These cookies do not expire when you close your browser. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until you delete them or they expire. By assigning your computer a unique identifier, we are able to create a database of your previous choices and preferences which can be provided by us automatically, saving you time and effort on future visits. For example, after you make a purchase, if you decide to make another purchase, your shipping address may have been retained and will only need to be confirmed.

  * Use of 'Do Not Track' Browser Settings

3M's Internet Sites are compatible with 'Do Not Track' browser functionality. 'Do Not Track' is a browser setting that provides a single, simple, persistent choice to opt out of third-party web tracking. If your web browser has the 'Do Not Track' setting enabled, advertising cookies will not be set on 3M web properties.

Certain countries, including members of the European Union, require your consent to the use of cookies when you visit 3M websites. If you access a 3M website from one of these countries, you will be presented with information regarding your options, including the option to accept or reject certain categories of cookies. You will be able to change these settings on subsequent visits. Please note that you will not be able to opt out of receiving certain cookies that are strictly necessary for the delivery of a service requested by you.

  * Cookie Settings on Your Computer

At any time when visiting a 3M Internet site, clicking on the “Cookie Preferences” link at the bottom of each page allows you to access information on cookies and change your settings.

Although you are not required to accept cookies when you visit a 3M Internet Site, you may be unable to use all of the functionality of the site if you reject certain cookies.

In addition, your browser may allow you to adjust settings to accept or reject cookies, or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer.
